Ron Forbes

206.409.6562 r@ronforbes.me Product Manager | Game Developer Venice, CA www.ronforbes.me

Summary

Product manager with 10 years of experience in leading game development teams across computer vision, mobile apps, and esports events. I'm a human-centric leader that believes an inspired, results-focused, growth-oriented team is a powerful competitive advantage.

Experience

Senior Development Manager | Esports @ Riot Games | 2014-2018

- Aligned teams and stakeholders on vision and strategy of League of Legends esports events
- Managed product development of annual roadmap of global events, including Mid-season Invitational, Rift Rivals, World Championship and All-Star Event, delivering hundreds of millions of hours of viewership, substantially improved sentiment and advocacy for the sport
- Mentored, coached and managed growth of product leadership team members and mentees throughout the organization

Senior Program Manager | Xbox @ Microsoft | 2009-2014

 Led end-to-end product development of key features of Kinect, the motion sensing accessory for Xbox One and Xbox 360, including biometric recognition, skeletal tracking and fitness tracking systems

Founder and CEO | Omega Entertainment | 2012-2014

• Independently developed and published two games (Vector Arena, Block Party) across Windows and Windows Phone platforms

Software Development Engineer in Test | Internet Explorer @ Microsoft | 2007-2009

 Developed quality assurance tools and tests for user experience and privacy features of Internet Explorer 8

Education

Certified Scrum Master / Certified Product Owner | Mountain Goat Software | 2014 B.S in Computer Science | Virginia Tech | Blacksburg, VA | 2003-2007

Awards & Distinctions

Chesterfield County Distinguished Alum
MEGA Mentors Distinguished Alum
Patent award winner for innovation in biometric recognition
Keynote speaker @ E3 2009 and CES 2010
Trustworthy Computing Award: InPrivate Browsing